ちょほいとあんたら
あんたら漁師だろう
悪いけど　船　出してくれよ
俺らこれから八丈島に行きてぇんだがよ
本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:东吾 king  翻译:念白白 poopy   校对:木落 时间轴:wcaster
Hey, you guys...
We wish to go to Hachijo Island.
You're fishermen, right?
Take us there.
この愚か者が　監視一つできんのか
You fool.
You can't even watch someone?
So, Gaikotsu, what was that carriage?
それで蓋骨　あの駕籠は何
寺社見回り組と武家見回り組の与力がそれぞれ護衛についていたんだ
Both the Shrine and Temple
and the Samurai Patrols
were guarding it.
It was almost certainly the Insect Magistrate!
おそらく蟲奉行の駕籠と見て間違いないだろう
蟲奉行ですって
The Insect Magistrate?
It's a well-kept secret, but every summer,
秘密裏とされているが
毎年蟲奉行は夏になると　江戸を出て「離れ」と呼ばれる場所に一人でこもるらしい
the Magistrate goes somewhere known as the Refuge,
and dwells there alone.
しかし　それがどこなのか　未だに分からないのだ
But no one knows where it is.
ちょっと　なんで教えてくれなかったの
Wait... Why didn't you tell me?
知ってたら　私がこの手で殺してやったのに
If I'd known, I'd have killed her myself.
使い走りの貴様にできるものか
That would be impossible. You just run errands.
冗談じゃないわ
Don't be stupid.
蟲奉行所の抹殺こそが私たち「蟲狩り」の最大の目的なのよ
Murdering the Insect Magistrate
the ultimate goal of the Insect Hunters.
もちろんだ　それを貴様がおめおめと逃げ帰ったせいで　台無しにしたんだ
Indeed,
and your failure to do your
job ruined our chances.
分かったわよ　蟲奉行所の誰かに　その「離れ」って場所を聞き出して来るわ
Fine, fine.
I'll go find someone at the magistrate's office
and ask them where the Refuge is.
しくじるなよ　死にたくなかったらな
If you don't want to die, don't screw up.
Go, then, insects.
それじゃ　行きなさい　蟲たち
Mitsuki's Honey Trap
蟲が出たぞ
An insect!
Now to the east!
今度は東だ
Another one!
また出た
何やらお忙しそうですね　皆さん
Looks like everyone is very busy.
Lately, there have been way too many insects.
最近蟲出すぎでしょう
And once they show up, they run.
しかも出てきた途端にすぐ逃げちゃうし
ったく　どうなってんだよ
What's going on?
僕はできる子　でも疲れた
I can do this!
But I'm tired...
どうしたんですか　皆さん　元気がありませんよ
What's wrong, everyone?
You look tired!
張り切って行きましょう
Let's get back to work!
仁兵衛君　少し休んだら
Jinbei-kun, why don't you rest?
君だけずっとお勤めしてるけど　大丈夫
You're the only one who hasn't
had a break. Are you okay?
そうよ　皆交代制でやってるんだから
That's right.
The rest of us are working in shifts.
何をおっしゃいます
What are you saying?
この月島仁兵衛　江戸が大事の時に　休息など取っていられません
I, Tsukishima Jinbei, cannot
rest while Edo is in danger!
じ　仁兵衛君
J-Jinbei-kun...
大変です
Trouble!
今度は深川に蟲が
Now there's an insect in Fukakawa.
よし　行こう
Okay, let's go.
仁兵衛君　君はもう休んでいいから
Jinbei-kun!
You should rest.
まだ自分はやります
I can still fight.
いいかい　これは与力の僕の命令だからね
Listen to me.
As your superior, this is my order.
He will be my target...
ターゲットはこいつにキ　マ　リ
Mikawaya
どうかなされましたか
Is something wrong?
ハナオが切れてしまって
My shoelace broke!
そ　それは難儀ですね
That's a shame.
ありがとうございます
Thank you!
い　いいえ　では　失礼いたします
Not at all.
Goodbye, then.
Um...
あの　ついでと言っては何ですが
Might you be able to help me?
あたし　道に迷ってるんですけど
I seem to have lost my way...
それはお困りでしょう
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
Ah, my bra is showing!
胸元が乱れております
I w-will be happy to show you around!
この月島仁兵衛がご案内仕ります
私は蜜月と申します
My name is Mitsuki.
Nice to meet you, Jin-san.
よろしくね　仁さん
He's a kid and he looks stupid.
こいつガキでバカっぽいから　私にかかればイチコロよ
He'll be easy prey.
今度こそぶった切ってやるっぜ
This time, I'll cut you in half.
近くでまた蟲が出ました
Another insect nearby.
ちょっと待ってろ　こっちのやつ退治したらすぐ…
Just a second!  Once I've finished this one...
で　また逃がした
It ran away.
それで　蜜月殿　宿はどちらなのですか
So, Mitsuki-dono, where is your inn?
えっ　ええと
Hmm...
There are insects over there and there...
あっちとあっちは蟲が出てるから
Huh?
ううん　なんでもないなんでもない　そっちかな
Ah, it's nothing!
Maybe there?
なるほど　日本橋のほうですね
Oh! Near Nihonbashi.
So that's it...
そうですか　蜜月殿は人探しでこの江戸に
You're here, in Edo, to find someone?
Yes.
はい
一目でいいから会いたくて
I only want to see them, even once!
なんと健気な
How noble!
ぜひ　お手伝いさせてください
I'd love to help you!
Men are such fools.
男なんて　ちょろいもんよ
楽しい人ですね　蜜月殿は
You're a fun person, Mitsuki-dono!
やばっ　無涯君
Oh, no! Mugai-kun!
おお　これは無涯殿
Oh, Mugai-dono!
へい　退いててて
Out of the way!
These are fresh from the river!
活きがいい魚だ　飛び出ちゃうよ
仁さん　着物の中に鰻が
Jin-san!
An eel got inside my kimono!
取ってくださいましー
Please get it out!
What?
なんと
誰か　拾ってくれ
Someone get those for me!
なんと
Mitsuki?
蜜月か
It's been a while, Mugai-kun.
お久しぶり　無涯君
What are you doing?
何をしている
うん　ちょっとね
Oh, nothing.
I don't know what you're planning,
何を企んでるか知らぬが
とんだ外れを引いたな
but you've chosen the wrong one.
外れ　あのバカのこと
The wrong one? That idiot?
I got it! I got it!
取ったり取ったり　掴み取ったり
I got it!
「掴み取ったよ　蜜月殿」
何言ってんだか　あいつはもう私の魅力にメロメロよ
What is he talking about?
That boy is already in love with me.
それで　蟲奉行所にはどんな人がいるの
So,
what kind of people work at the Insect Magistrate?
そうですね　美しい太刀筋で岩をも切る恋川春菊殿
Let's see...
Koikawa Shungiku-dono,
whose majestic strikes can cleave rock.
華麗なる発破と忍術の火鉢殿
Hibachi-dono, with her elegant
ninjutsu and explosions!
鉄壁の防御を誇る式神使いの一乃谷天間殿
Ichinotani Tenma-dono,
whose shikigami are invincible!
皆さん素晴らしい方ばかりです
They're all wonderful.
うん　うん　それから
And?
後は与力の松ノ原小鳥殿
Matsunohara Kotori-dono, our superior.
で　その上にもう一人偉い人がいるでしょう
And there's someone above him, isn't there?
偉い人
Above him?
ほら　あなた達のトップに立ってる人よ
Like your leader...
The person at the top...
一番偉い人
Oh, you mean them?
おお　あの人のことですか
こんにちは　仁兵衛様
Hello, Jinbei-sama.
おお　これはお春殿
Oh, Oharu-dono!
Wh-What?
な　何よ　何なのよ　この巨桃女は
Who is this giant peach woman?
今日はお休みだったんですか
Are you not working today?
はい　自分は平気だったんですが
That's right!
I was fine, but Kotori-dono ordered it.
小鳥殿に無理やり命じられまして
しかもこいつ　私の存在　忘れてない
And I think he's forgotten about me!
Just when it was getting good, too!
せっかくいいところだったのに
仁さん　あっち行きましょう
Jin-san!
We're going over there, Jin-san!
Are you okay, Oharu-dono!
大丈夫ですか　お春殿
What?
なんと
いったたた　転んじゃいました
Ow...
I tripped and spilled my water...
まずい　今日やってきたこと全部持ってかれる
Oh, no...
This will wreck everything I've accomplished today!
何とかしなくっちゃ
I have to do something.
あった
There!
Oharu-dono, please dry yourself with this.
お春殿　これで拭いてください
I couldn't...
そんな　仁兵衛様の着物が濡れてしまいます
Your kimono will get wet.
仁さん　私も転んじゃった
Jin-san! I tripped, as well!
大丈夫ですか
Are you okay?
ありがとうございます
Thank you.
巨桃女
Giant peach woman!
蜜月殿も濡れてしまいましたか
Did you also get wet, Mitsuki-dono?
では　この褌を
Then I'll take off this fundoshi.
ふざけんじゃないわよ
What is wrong with him?!
なんであの巨桃女が着物で私が褌のわけ
Why does the giant peach
woman get his kimono,
while I get his underwear?
I'm done with the honey trap.
まあ　お色気作戦は中止
あのムカツク巨桃女は利用してやる
I'll use that stupid peach woman...
Oharu,
お春　ドレー閉まっておくれ
close up the shop.
はい
Okay.
What's wrong, Oharu?
どうした　お春
お春　お春
Oharu?
月島　昨日の分までしっかり働きなさいよ
Tsukishima, you rested yesterday,
so you'd better work hard today.
頼むぜ　兄ちゃん
Good luck, kid.
はい　お任せください
Right, leave it to me!
どうかなされましたか
Is something wrong?
お春ちゃんが昨日の夜から行方不明なんだそうだ
Oharu-chan went missing last night.
な　なんと　お春殿が
What?
Oharu-dono is missing?
仁さん
Jin-san!
Mitsuki-dono...
蜜月殿
今日は大事なお願いがあるんだけど
I have something important to ask you today...
I'm sorry, but I can't help you right now.
申し訳ありません　今はそれどころではなくて
そ　それは昨日お春殿が着ていた…
That's what Oharu-dono was wearing yesterday!
Yup.
そう　どう　似合う
Do I look good in it?
はい　よく似合ってます
Yes, you look very good.
そういうこと言ってんじゃないわよ
That isn't the point!
私があの巨桃女をさらったのよ
I kidnapped that giant peach woman!
えっ
北にある美山村に一人で来て頂戴
Come alone to Miyamamura, north of town.
じゃないと　私の操る蟲たちに　あの巨桃女　おいしく食べられちゃうわよ
Otherwise,
my insects will devour
that peach woman.
さっそく出やがったな
There it is.
行くわよ　月島
Let's go, Tsukishima.
で　月島は
Eh? Where's Tsukishima?
いなくなっちゃった
He's gone...
ここは
Where am I?
You're awake?
お目覚め
You're going to be a hostage,
to lure Tsukishima Jinbei.
あなたには月島仁兵衛を誘き出すための人質になってもらうわ
何のために
Why?
あんたなんかに教える必要ないでしょう
I have no reason to tell you.
This space belongs to me alone.
ここは私だけの空間
住んでた人はどうしたのですか
What happened to those who lived here?
住人なんて要らないのよ
It doesn't need any occupants.
人間なんかうざいだけで信用できないんだから
Humans are annoying and you can't trust them.
Aren't you lonely?
寂しくはありませんか
寂しい？
Lonely?
こんな所でたった一人で暮らすなんて寂しすぎます
Living here alone would be too lonely for me.
町にはいろんな人の笑顔があるからこそ
I think it's fun in the city
皆楽しく暮らせるんだと思います
because you can see everyone smiling.
Shut up!
うるさいわね
あんた何かに何が分かるのよ
What do you know?
美山村はこの辺りのはず
Miyamamura should be here somewhere.
しかしここは…
But there's nothing...
どこにいらっしゃいますか　蜜月殿
Where are you? Mitsuki-dono?
お春殿
Oharu-dono!
Jeez, you're both obnoxious.
どいつもこいつもうるさいな
蜜月殿　お春殿はどこに
Mitsuki-dono, where is Oharu-dono?
If you want to find out,
教えて欲しかったら
あんた達のトップ　蟲奉行がどこにいるか言いなさい
then tell me where your leader,
the Insect Magistrate, is.
さぁ
Tell me!
蜜月殿　一つ言わせていただきます
Mitsuki-dono, I do want to tell you something.
あなたは間違っている
What you are doing is wrong!
はっ？！
気付いてないかも知れませんが
You may not realize it, but what
you're doing here is very bad!
蜜月殿は今とても悪いことをしています
こんなことはすぐやめるべきです
You should stop this right now!
確かに昨日きちんと道案内できず
It's true that I upset you while I was escorting you yesterday, but－
何？私に説教してんの　こいつ
What? Is he actually lecturing me?
蜜月殿を怒らせてしまったかもしれませんが
Shut up! Shut up!
うるさいうるさい
いいから蟲奉行の離れがどこにあるのか答えなさい
Just tell me where the Insect Magistrate's Refuge is!
Mitsuki-dono...
蜜月殿
自分　蟲奉行様というお方に会ったことはありません
I have never even met the Insect Magistrate.
すみません
I'm sorry!
自分はまだ新米ゆえ　蟲奉行様のお住まいやら離れなどまったく存じません
I'm still new, so I don't know where
the magistrate lives or might go!
とぼけんじゃないわよ
Don't lie to me!
とぼけてません
I'm not.
ですが　今から小鳥殿に聞いてまいります
But I will go ask Kotori-dono.
待っててください
Please wait here!
そういって仲間をここに集めるつもりね
So you'll keep me here while you
get the rest of your friends?
そうはさせないわ
I won't allow that.
ここは一体って
What is this?
蟲
An insect?
You're a really stupid samurai, aren't you?
本当どうしようもない　へっぽこ侍ね
Mitsuki-dono...
蜜月殿
お春殿
Oharu-dono!
仁兵衛様
Jinbei-sama!
あんたみたいなへっぽこ　一瞬でも利用しようとした私がバカだったわ
I was an idiot for thinking of trying
to use someone as stupid as you.
Jinbei-sama isn't stupid.
仁兵衛様はへっぽこではありません
仁兵衛様は強くて優しくて思いやりのある　立派なお侍です
He's strong, kind and caring...
He's a wonderful samurai.
お任せください　お春殿
Leave it to me, Oharu-dono!
信じるものは救われるって言いたいのかしら
You think all you have to do
is have faith and you'll be saved?
でもね　救われないのよ　実際は
That never happens!
今がチャンス
This is my chance.
私だって　仁兵衛様のお役に立てるんですから
I can help Jinbei-sama, too!
と　届かない
I c-can't reach...
Jinbei-sama!
仁兵衛様
お春殿
Oharu-dono!
ご無事ですか　お春殿
Are you okay, Oharu-dono?
Thank you very much, Jinbei-sama.
ありがとうございます　仁兵衛様
I won't let you escape.
逃がさないわよ
お春殿　危ない
Oharu-dono, watch out!
下には砂地獄　上からは建物
Sinking sand below,
and buildings falling from above!
There's nowhere to run...
逃げ場がない
ご安心ください
Don't worry.
いい方法を思いつきました
I had a great idea.
落ちてくる建物を使って　天井の穴まで上りましょう
We'll climb those falling buildings
to the hole on the roof!
Goal
Yay, yay!
J-Jinbei-sama...
仁　仁兵衛様
なんて素晴らしいお考えなんでしょう
What a wonderful idea!
Let's go!
参りましょう
はい
Yes.
どうやらぺちゃんこになって死にたいようね
Looks like you want to get squashed.
お春殿　まず自分の腰につかまって
Oharu-dono, first grab on to my hips!
Right.
はい
参れ
Forward!
背中へ
To my back!
頭を踏み台に
Jump on my head!
はい
Right!
何と
What?
N-No way.
嘘 あいつら
They're seriously planning to try for the exit?
もう一回
参れ
このまま出口の穴まで行くつもり？
背中へ
頭を踏み台に
Now jump on my shoulders!
蜜月殿
Mitsuki-dono...
自分は知っていますよ
I know something!
I know how nice you are.
どんなにお優しい方なのか
そんな優しいあなたが
You're so nice,
こんなことをするはずがありません
you would never do anything like this!
H-How dumb can you be?
バ　バカに程があるわ
After all this, he still trusts me?
この状況で　まだ私を信じてるの
なるほど
I understand...
蜜月殿は誰かに脅されているんですね
You're being threatened by someone!
そうだったのですか？
Were you?
So you can have faith in me.
だったら自分を信じてください
お守りしますから
I'll protect you!
What is this?
何それ
何なの　あいつら　ふざけんじゃないわよ
What the hell is wrong with those two?!
な　何だ
What is that?
別々にいた蟲達が
All the different insects...
一斉に飛んで行っちゃった
They all flew off at once?
The exit is so close, but insects are everywhere
and no more buildings are falling!
出口はすぐそこなのに　蟲ばかりで建物が落ちてこない
Idiot... I won't drop any more.
バーカ　もう落とさないだわ
Look at that.
ほら　見なさい
No matter what you say,
どんなに偉そうなこと言ったって
if you believe in that idiot,
this is what happens!
へっぽこばかを信じたら　そんな目に遭うのよ
Oharu-dono, are you safe?
お春殿　ご無事ですか
Yes.
はい
This is why you can't lower your guard...
いや　油断大敵とはこのことですね
はい　次は用意周到に参りましょう
Yes, let's be more careful next time.
Right!
はい
They're laughing...
笑ってる
What are they laughing at?
何を笑ってるの　あいつら
I think it's fun in the city
町にはいろんな人の笑顔があるからこそ
because you can see everyone smiling.
楽しく暮らせるんだと思います
Always be ready for a fight!
常住戦陣
Let's make it out this time.
今度こそここから出ましょう
Yes, Jinbei-sama.
はい　仁兵衛様
Don't think it's over yet.
何かっこつけてんのよ
I still have more...
こっちにはまだ…
insects to call!
蟲がいるんだから
You're going to die here!
ここでくたばりなさい
I found you, insects!
見つけたぜ　蟲ケラ共
Guys!
皆さん
Repentance Slash.
懺斬り
Hydrangea Blossoms.
紫陽花玉
Full-Power Slap!
全力突っ張り
I finally got to kill you...
ようやくぶった切ってやったぜ
Yes, I feel better.
うん　すっとした
一ヶ所に移動したから　何かあると思ったけど
I wondered why they were all
converging in one place.
Everyone,
皆さん　お勤めお疲れ様です
good work!
You...
兄ちゃん
What are you doing here?
何であんたがここに？
Jinbei-sama, Mitsuki-san is gone.
仁兵衛様　蜜月さんがいません
Mitsuki-dono...
蜜月殿
Mugai-kun, that Tsukishima guy
doesn't know anything, does he?
無涯君　あの月島ってやつ　何も知らなかったわ
You were right. I picked the wrong guy.
無涯君の言った通り　とんだ外れを引いたみたいよ
That wasn't what I meant.
そういう意味で外れと言ったわけじゃない
Then, what did you mean?
じゃ　どういう意味よ
I'm not sure I know myself.
さてな　俺にもよく分からん
Even I don't understand that idiot!
あんなバカ　私だって理解に苦しむわよ
Tsukishima Jinbei?
月島仁兵衛か？
I'll remember that name.
覚えておくわ
Hey, you guys...
ちょほいとあんたら
We wish to go to Hachijo Island.
俺らこれから八丈島に行きてぇんだがよ
You're fishermen, right?
あんたら漁師だろう
Take us there.
悪いけど　船　出してくれよ
There's nothing on that island.
島に何かなーんにもねぇぜ
What would you want there?
あんたら何の用があるんだ
No, we're told there's a girl hiding there.
いいや　小娘が一匹囲われてるらしい
Gaikotsu, is leaving Mitsuki here all right?
蓋骨　蜜月はつれて行かなくていいのか？
We don't need that useless girl anymore.
あんな役立たずは無用
When we're back from the island, I'll kill her.
島から戻って来たら　この俺が始末する
Very well.
そうか
Let's go, men...
行くぞ　お前達
It's time for revenge!
復讐の時だ
Next Time
Let's go to Hachijo Island!
いざ八丈島へ
頑張ってください
Good luck.
Supposedly, the island has two big mountains.
島には高い山が二つあるとか
嫌な予感が…
I have a bad feeling about this...
何と　そこにあったか　二つ山
What? There they are!
I knew that was going to happen!
やっぱりですか
Next time, on Mushibugyou:
次回　蟲奉行　「蟲狩強襲！！八丈島の変！！」
The Insect Hunters Attack.
The Insect Hunters Attack!!
Battle of Hachijo Island!!
Battle of Hachijo Island.